So hello namaskar friends welcome again to
our channel Learning Information so
today I am going to tell you that the medi
claim means the hospitalization
claim form has two parts, one
cashless and one reimbursement so how to
fill up the reimbursement form what is the process how
can you submit it, I
will tell you the whole thing in this video so let's start so
let's first know that medi is a
claim hasp form and there are
two parts, I will explain to you, first the claim
facility of hasp
or medi claim and how to get it processed, the
first one has two parts which are
medium
or medium, these are two parts you can see one part is
claim
and this is
reimbursement, okay the topic is this, this
is reimbursement, it is
through hospitalization, means through
hospital, they process it through
hospital, they
process it through
and you have to do self process,
self
process or what does this mean, what is that
which  There is an individual policy and
a corporate policy, so
you have to submit the corporate policy yourself
in the entire company and the individual
policies can also be done through the agent, the
agent can also do it here,
okay, so as you have to download the rebusment form
online yourself, after that
you have to print out the form,
after that you can fill up the form and submit it through the agent also,
directly to the company
which is your TPA company and you
can also self courier it, okay,
you can process it in these and
you can also process it through the agent, so
let's see how the form looks, so
as I have printed out one form, I have
printed out two forms, this is the
full form of Media Assist which is TP, you can
process it through these also
and there is a form which we mean PPN
Committee, National United Oriental New
India and these four companies, these companies can
also work in this form, this part will be
Y, this part A, you can see this
claim  You can also fill up the form from Part A
and submit it and this is
your part, that is, the field by insured will have to be
filled up by yourself and the Part B
form has two parts, Part B
every form has two parts, Part A and
Part B. Part B will have to be filled up by the hospital,
okay, it will have to be done
by the hospital, you will have to get it filled up from the hospital,
so you can see this a little bit
and how do you fill Part A,
basically it will be a little better to fill it from this form
and
if you are personally filling the TP form of Media Assist,
you can also do it from this, you
can do it from both of them, it will be a little better with these,
okay, I will give you the link of every form
in the description, you can
check out the firm, so Part A which will have to be
filled up, you will have to give the policy number,
your policy number is individual policy
number, if it is an individual policy then the policy
number has to be given, if it is a corporate policy
then it has to be left, okay,
you do not have to do anything or nothing right now, company name  You have to write the PP
ID number, the PAP card ID number
here and whatever the TP card number is
902 38, you have to write your name in
whose name you want to claim the
remittance claim, you have to write the name here or you
can write any name
Ram
Sharma Ram Sharma, you have to write the complete address
like
Kolkata is fine, you
can write 759, write the city address or the given
address, after that details of insurance
history, current cover by any or medical,
currently you have got the patient admitted through any mediclaim
or have taken any facility, then
yes or no, if no, then no, if yes, then yes, if yes, then
you have to write here
which company you have taken it from, if it is
of the same company, then you have to write the name of the company, if you
have any other company, then its name has to be
written here, after that you have to give the policy number also, it has to be
written like 3 4 5 6 7 8 no 02 3,
okay, how much will the cover be, means
if there is 5 lakh in that policy  So you can take 5 lakhs
here, okay
and there is nothing here,
what is the diagnosis on this, means what is the problem of the patient,
what was the problem of the patient at that time, due to
which problem the
patient was admitted, you have to basically
write that, I will write LT, I will write Low Respiratory
Infection and basically you don't have to do anything,
you have to fill the details of in person
hospitalization, hospitalization details, that is, the
complete details of the patient who was admitted here, okay,
basically the name is Ram
Sharma, Ram Sharma, you have to fill the complete details,
whatever it is, you have to write the complete
occupation, Ag Service Self Apple Home Maker,
whatever it is, you have to
write basically the address Kolkata, details of hospital,
name of hospitalization, name of the admitted hospital, you have to write it, here,
basically the
name of the hospital has to be written, I will write Apollo, Apollo
Hospital, I have to write the name of the hospital, room
category, in which bed was he admitted, was he
admitted in day bed or in single bed or
twin sharing or general bed, if  If it is a date then you have to
tick in D care, if it is single then you have to
click on single bed
and tick mark it,
basically I do it in single video,
hospitalization due to injury, illness,
maternity illness means that
if the patient has any emergency complication
then it is an illness and you know about injury, if there is
any accidental problem then you have to tick it, if there is any other accidental problem then
you have to tick it, basically if there is an injury then
you have to write the date of injury, if it is a delivery case then
you have to write the delivery date and if there is any illness, that is, if there is any
emergency problem then
you have to write the date of admission here basically,
if I write today 7
11 here, date of admission
basically you have to enter the same admission date
11 ok, you have to enter the time, if you do not
know then leave it, you can see the bill
which you will have, the print out of the bill which will be
provided by the hospital
there  It will be written that the admission date and
admission time will be written, it will definitely be written, please check the
date of discharge, the
day on which the discharge happened, I do it after five days or four days,
here I will put the 12th date, the
research research time is the
same, please see there, injury given case,
given case, if there is an injury, then how did the injury happen, did you
fall due to a self-incident, did you get self-
injury due to some other reason, if it is a road
traffic RTA case, it means there was an accident with a bike
or any road trough
accident, then click on it and tick
mark it and substance abuse means if there is any
alcohol history, then basically
you do not have to do this part, okay,
you do not have to do this part, basically
you do not have to do this part, you can see it, you do
not have to do it, after that you have to do like
report of police, if there is an injury, if it is an
accidental case, then you have to tick
mark it, otherwise you have to leave it,
basically after that comes the details of claim,  The
details of claim comes, which is the entire
expense that you have incurred,
you have to write all that in details on this page. Pra Hasp
friends, if you incurred some expenses before admission, that is, you
spent something, then basically you have to enter the
amount here. This basically has to be entered.
Post hospitalization, which happens
after hospitalization, if you
buy medicines, get some tests done,
if you get any OPD checkup done, then this will
come in the post hospitalization record.
If it is for ambulance, then it will come in the ambulance charge. For
how many days before the pre hospitalization period are you claiming?
Maximum 30 days before and after two months, that is, the
expenses of one month before hospitalization and the expenses of two months after hospitalization, you
can claim it all together.
And how do you basically have to claim this?
You have to claim this within 15 days. If you claim
in Part Part, it will be good. If you
claim in Part P, it will be good.
And on this page you have to fill
Hasp expenses, if some amount is
not completed at the time of admission in the hospital, then some
deducted amount.  If you have to make some
payment then that amount has to be
entered here, if suppose you have to make a
payment of Rs. 5000 then you have to enter the amount here,
if you have
not got cashless facility in hospitalization and have made the full payment then you have to
enter the full amount of payment here, okay basically
and here you do not have to do anything and here
you will claim for how many days of post hospitalization, two months or 10 days
or after 15 days, that is,
whatever expenses have been incurred after hospitalization, you
will claim that, that is your choice, but it will be
better to claim in Pat Pat,
after that you do not have to do anything here, you have to
write all this, you have to write the total, how much will it be after adding the
total amount, you have to
write the total, if it is 40000
then write 40000, if it is one lakh then
write one lakh, if it is 5, then write it,
but please see this, take it with a little care,
okay, it is not that difficult,
you can tell, you
You have to enter the details of the bill, if the bill is
your return number or the bill
number, if it is 4, 5, 6 then the
5th number is the bill number, the final bill
given to you by the hospital,
you will get it there, the final bill is here, okay, and
give the date here, give the discharge date,
whatever will be the resurge date, give the bill date
here, and
write the name of the hospital issued by, okay, okay, write Apollo,
write Apollo here, write the
hospital main bill amount here,
if it is 50000 then write 50000
here, and basically you do not have to do anything here, and
you have to go straight down,
here you have to give your primary bank
account details, you have to give the PAN card number,
basically the PAN card number, bank
account number, any bank account number, you
can give the patient's account number, you can
give any other account number as well,
you have to give basically the patient's, it would be good
if there is a problem, if there is something different then you
can give another account as well, basically  You can
try that
if you can give the account number of the policy holder or the institute in the policy, then it will be
good, okay, then it will
reduce a little bit of problem, this is done,
your part, your part has to be
filled completely and after that you simply have to
sign in the next page, if you want to sign, then give
full signature, okay,
give full signature, and this place, whatever
your place is, if it is Kolkata,
Kolkata, if it is Mumbai, then give Kolkata, give
your date, give the
date of the day on which you will submit, okay, it will be
better, after that this part is the complete
hospital form, the
hospital will fill it up completely, take it to the hospital,
you can take a discharge copy
and take this form with you, they will
fill it up here, okay, after that
you can submit it directly, you
can also do it through an agent in the company, if there is an agent,
if it is a corporate policy, then
you can send it directly to the TPA company
through courier and one more thing  Important thing,
whatever document you are sending, make
a photocopy of all the documents,
keep it with you, receive it,
okay, if it is possible that
after sending it, it gets lost somewhere, if
something happens somewhere, then you can submit that copy again,
okay, definitely make this copy, then in this way
you can claim, rehabilitation
claim and catheter, you know that it is done
through the hospital, so that was all
in today's video, and if you like the video, then
please like and share and subscribe
to the channel.